Lafayette mss., 1572-1939 LMC 2326
Lilly Library
- Manuscripts
  - Chronological
    - Lafayette to Jean Pierre Boyer (President of Haiti) - Introducing Fanny Wright, 1829, October 28; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to Robert Dale Owen - In reply to his request for some views on the "Life and Work of Fanny Wright", 1829, October 28; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to James Monroe - Introducing Monsieur Pepin, the son of a "schall" manufacturer of Paris, 1829, October 29; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to Jared Sparks - Even though Lafayette may later himself use the data he is sending Sparks, he freely permits it to appear in Sparks' projected work, but with his usual kindliness suggests that should his observations of other days seem likely to offend some individual, they could be softened, 1829, November 15; Photostat 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to William Whitlock - Thanking him for the American periodicals, 1829, November 17; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to Cassan - Condolences, 1829, November 17; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Carlo Guiseppe Guglielmo Botta to Monsieur Cavena, 1829, November 25; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to Sparks - He is sending some historical papers - mentions the son of de Grasse, 1829, November 25; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette to Jared Sparks - He will write his own Memoirs but they will be published by his children after he passes on, 1829, December 13; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette - Memorandums, 1829; ADS (Box 3, Folder 37)
      "NOTE - The first memo is Lafayette's reply to Grenier, the second is his response to Bonne, and on the reverse is the short speeches made by Lafayette's son George, in his own hand."
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - Encloses a copy of his letter to the National Guards of France and Paris bearing on his dismissal and asks Duponceau to see that they are translated and published, 1830, January 8; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Tracy Lafayette to Monsieur Mahan at Metz - Our poor sick ones remain about the same, we are still very much worried, 1830, January 8; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - James Gambier to W. T. Eglinson, 1830, February 11; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "Naval officer who replaced Howe in the command of the British Fleet in New York Harbor - 1778 - James Gambier (1756-1833) - his ancestors were French Protestants. He entered the British Navy at an early age and in 1778 was Post Commander. His ship, the Frigate "Raleigh" was engaged in the reduction of Charleston, S.C. in 1780. In the War of 1812 Gambier was at the head of the Commission that negotiated the Treaty, which was concluted and signed at Ghent December 24, 1814. Gambier was made Admiral of the Fleet by William IV."
    - Lafayette to Clarkson - On slavery, 1830, February 13; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette - "I am personally obliged to their (Balmarin and Raimbaud) zeal and still more so for their faithful secrecy in fitting up the ship that happily brought me to the American shore", 1830, March 5; ADS (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Includes typed copy
    - Lafayette to Louis McLane, the American Minister in London, 1830, March 12; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "Young Protestants have no cause for complaint of priestly influence in the College de Louis le Grand - later correspondence indicates that McLane was at this time about to send his son to school in Paris. Louis McLane (1786-1857), son of Allan McLane, one of the prominent figures in the American Revolution, was a volunteer in the defense of the British attack on Baltimore in 1814. He was the American Minister to England, 1829-1831."
    - Claude Victor-Perrin, Duc de Bellune, to Monsieur Aubry, Maire de la Commune de Boigny pres Orleans, 1830, March 17; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Colonel Stevens to Hon. Martin van Buren, Secretary of State, 1830, March 20; Typed document 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - John Augustine Washington to "Sir", 1830, March 26; ADS (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "John Augustine Washington was the great-grandson of John Augustine Washington, General Washington's brother. His mother was Hannah Lee, the daughter of Richard Henry Lee."
    - Charles Nodier to Delangle, libraire, 1830, March; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Mr. Sparks - Refers to the Coblentz and Pilnitz conferences, 1830, March 28; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to James Brown - A long letter on many subjects, 1830, March 28; Photostat 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - General Bomford to Du Ponceau about the cut glass Lafayette has ordered shipped to France, 1830, March 29; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "George Bomford (1780-1848) was a West Pointer who served in the War of 1812 and became a Lieutenant Colonel. He was the inventor of a bomb cannon called "columbiads." His pattern was developed by Dahlgren adn used up to the time of the Civil War, when the Rodman was adopted."
    - Lafayette to Mr. Low - About his copy-books of 1781 Campaign in America, 1830, April 4; ADS (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Col. John Stevens to Andrew Jackson, 1830, April 7; Typed document 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to M. Justin - On the newspaper account of Lafayette's speech at the Lorraine dinner, 1830, April 21; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Du Ponceau - Pleads for an adjustment by the American Government for the claims of Basmarein and Rainbault, armorers of Bordeaux, who furnished supplies during the American Revolution, 1830, April 25; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Joel Poinsett, in America - On the French affairs of 1830, 1830, April 28; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to McLane - On the Mexico-Texas complication. Introducing Vincent Nolte, 1830, May 11; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "The Mr. Nolte who carried this letter of introduction, is the Nolte who appears in the novel "Anthony Adverse." He was the author of "Fifty Years a Merchant," a very interesting description of the business life of that period."
    - Lafayette's letter introducing Dr. Kirkland to Sir Charles Morgan, 1830, May 18; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "NOTE - Dr. Kirkland was Lafayette's host as President of Harvard College, in 1824."
    - Sending copies of lettesr referring to the Virginia Campaign of 1781, 1830, June 24; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Harriet Preble - Writes about her translations of Fenimore Cooper's books, 1830, June 26; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to former Minister James Brown - On the French political situation - "The King, his son, and M. de Polignac are obstinate", 1830, June 27; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Madame Sapey - "At present then we must decide on a coup d'etat", 1830, June 30; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to J. S. Skinner, 1830, July 1; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to S. B. Denison at Paris - He will permit some responsible party to take measurements and drawings of the Badge that General Washington used to wear as "member of our Cincinnati Society", 1830, July 12; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - Speaks of Levasseur's Book, and of Jared Sparks, 1830, July 17; Photostat 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Monsieur Borelly - About the elections, 1830, July 24; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Monsieur Cassan - Lists his house guests, which include six Americans, 1830, July 25; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette's official order of 5 o'clock A.M. to the Commanders of the Post to aid, with force, Capt. Marion in taking to the Hotel de Ville, all the furnishings of the Tuilleries, if at any time they are in danger of being destroyed or stolen, 1830, July 30; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette, as Commander-in-Chief, asks the Mayor of Meudon to return the three guns seized yesterday at 7 o'clock in the evening, 1830, August 2; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to Guizot - Mentions Bureaux Pusy, 1830, August 10; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Invitation to the Municipal Banquet to be held in honor of General Lafayette, on August 15th, 1830, August 13; Printed document with autograph fill-ins (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to M. Sapey - Describing an interview with Louis Philippe, 1830, August 13-14; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "Monsieur Sapey (1775-1857) sat in Corps Legislative (1802-1808) in Chamger of Deputies (1817-1824) and was a liberal and re-elected in 1828. He supported Louis Philippe until 1848 in the Chamber of Deputies. In 1825 he became a member of Senate."
    - George Washington Lafayette to Jean Baptiste Genier at Brioude - His reply to a request from Grenier that he be recommended to the Department of Justice - Lafayette, the father, will write the following day, 1830, August 19; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      "NOTE - This is evidently a letter (of great length and difficult to decipher) from Jean Baptiste Grenier to George Washington Lafayette who transmits it to a colleague with a recommendation that Baptiste Grenier be named to an office in the Department of Justice. Lafayette, the father, will write the next day and George himself does not know a nomination which he is more desirous of seeing successful."
    - Cassan to Dupont de l'Eure, 1830, August 23; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Rondonneau to General Lafayette - An appeal, 1830, August 29; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lafayette to James Monroe - "Your warm interest in the fate of French freedom will ahve made you a hearty partaker in the triumph of the popular cause. It is exquisitely the victory of the people", 1830, September 7; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - James Henderson to Van Ransselear, 1830, September 18; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to Polloy - "I have sent your petition to the Chambre", 1830, October 10; ADS (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to Madame Willard, 1830, November 8; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - John Randolph of Roanoke to Louis McLane, 1830, November 8; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
      "John Randolph of Roanoke (1773-1833) was seventh in descent from Pocahontas by her marriage with John Rolfe. His widowed mother married St. George Tucker. Randolph was a strange youth and a broken romance romance with the Philadelphia beauty, Maria Ward, seems to have influenced his life, which was rather a stormy one. He and his relative, Thomas Jefferson, split on the subject of Napoleon. He clashed with Calhoun and insulted Henry Clay, who challened him, but the duel was without injury to either. Randolph was sent by President Jackson as Minister to Russia, but shortly returned to oppose the President on "Nullification." In person he was rather striking, being tall and slender, and with a fine speaking voice. He was eccentric and morose, but had a brilliant mind. Louis McLane (1786-1857), son of Captain Allan McLane, was Minister to England, 1829-1831."
    - Lafayette to Pataille - "Madame de Antoine, sister-in-law of Admiral Villeneuve, bears the same name as I, but we are not related. The similarity cause Villeneuve trouble during the Terror", 1830, November 25; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to Sparks - Speaking of the Washington papers and Lafayette papers that he had loaned Sparks, he says - "I wish that they may be of service to the Cause, the Country, and to you", 1830, November 26; Photostat 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Malibran to Lafayette, 1830, November 27; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
      "Malibran (Maria Garcia), cantatrice celebre (1808-1836)."
    - Lafayette to William Rawle, President of the Common Council - Thanking them for the resolution adopted by Philadelphia on the success of the affair of 1830, 1830, November 29; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to "My dear young Friends of the Academy of West Point", 1830, November 29; Photostat (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - Introducing Monsieur Weysse, a Professor of the Deaf Mute Institute of Paris, 1830, December 3; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - General Lafayette - The Greetings of the New York Society of the Cincinnati, 1830, December 4; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to General Sebastiani - He recommends de la Porte as Consul to Tallahassee, FL, 1830, December 18; ADS 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Includes photostat and typed translation into English
      "Horace Francois de la Porta, Count Sebastiani (1772-1851) was a Corsician who became one of Napoleon's most devoted partisans. He fought at Marengo, was wounded at Austerlitz, commanded an Army Corps in Spain and distinguished himself in the Russian Campaign (1812) and at Leipzig. He joined Napoleon on his return from Elba and was later an Ambassador at Naples and at London. He was made a Marshal in 1840."
    - Lafayette to Charles de Lasteyrie, 1830; Photostat 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Stockholder's ticket for Joseph Dugan - Canal between Philadelphia and Baltimore, 1830; Printed document with autograph fill-ins, signed (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Lafayette to the Lady Morgan, 1831, January 18; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Madame Bessau Lamegie, 1831, February 2; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Also includes description of letter from Fowler Napoleon Collection
    - Malibran to Lafayette, 1831, February 7; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Sparks - Has secured for him the friendly interest of Mr. Mignet (?), the author of a valuable book on the French Revolution, 1831, February 9; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Official paper signed by Lafayette as President of the Central Committee for the Relief of the Poles, 1831, February 10; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette concerning the Polish Committee, 1831, February 12; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - He has advised the King to banish the Duke of Modina, 1831, February 27; Photostat 3 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Washington Irving to Churchill C. Cambreling, 1831, March 2; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      "Washington Irving, while Secretary of Legation in London, writes to Churchill C. Cambreleng, who was then (1831) a member of Congress from New York and associated with John Jacob Astor for whom he travelled extensively over the world. The Randolph he gossips about was John Randolph "of Roanoke" who had accepted the Russian Mission in 1830 from President Jackson. He soon returned and joined issue with the President on the nullification question."
    - Lafayette to Gen. Zucchi - Speaks of his labors in behalf of the Italian cause, 1831, March 27; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Samuel Wood, Governor of the State Penitentiary (cover only), 1831, March 28; ADS (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Sutherland Dunglan, 1831, March 29; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau, 1831, March 31; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Monroe, 1831, March 31; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette - Covering the receipt of 4500 francs for the Poles, 1831, April 3; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to comte Chassenon, 1831, April 13; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Pelleport, 1831, May 19; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to General Romaino in Poland - Mentions Monsieur Gallois, Gustave Montebello, General Langermann, and General Fabrier, 1831, June 13; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - short note, 1831, June 16; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Feisthamel, 1831, June 21; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette - An appeal for help for an old soldier, M. Berger, 1831, June 22; ADS (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to General Sebastiani - Recommending the son of M. Frestel, stating that the father had "risked death for my family under the regime of proscription and the Terror, accompanied my son to the United States and stayed at the home of General Washington until my release from Olmutz", 1831, July 1; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Sir John Bowring - Referring to a German Nobleman who befriended him in Silesia, 1831, July 12; ADS (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to some friend whose family is to be his guest, 1831, July 16; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Villenave to his wife - A lengthy description of the ceremonies celebrating the first anniversary of the Revolution, 1831, July 30; Typed document 7 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette to Monsieur Garnier Paget - Mentions Monsieur Libeunski, 1831, September 3; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lafayette to Mrs. Ridgley - "Any fixed plan of a voyage to America can only be delightfully dreamed of", 1831, September 28; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - George W. Lafayette to Madame Montrobert. A sad ceremony prevents his calling, 1831, October 2; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - William Wirt to Abner Phelps, 1831, October 12; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      "William Wirt, 1772-1834, attorney general in 1824"
    - Lafayette to Charles Rogiers - Introducing Col. Poerio, a patriotic Neapolitan, who desires to enter the Belgian service, 1831, October 17; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Samuel F.B. Morse to DeWitt Bloodgood, New York - He is making studies at the Louvre...has not yet decided which Titian he will copy for Mr. Bloodgood...frequently Fenimore Cooper visits him when he is at work, and has given him a commission to copy a Rembrandt..."Our Nation's Guest, the increasingly illustrious Lafayette I have the happiness often to see...our sculptor Greenough has executed the most excellent bust of the General", 1831, October 31; ADS 4 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Joseph Anderson to Samuel Swartwant, 1831, November 9; ADS (Box 4, Folder 2)
      "A captain at Valley Forge - Joseph Anderson (1757-1837) was a law student when the war broke. He became an Ensign in the New Jersey line and served as a Captain at Monmouth and the siege of Yorktown. He retired after the war with the brevet rank of Major. In 1791 President Washington appointed him the Territorial Judge of the region south of the Ohio River and he assisted in drawing the Constitution of Tennessee and was the first U.S. Senator from the State, 1797-1815. Anderson was the first Comptroller of the United States serving from 1815 to 1836."
    - Lafayette - Mentioning Thier, Firmin, Didot and Henry Fournier, 1831, November 11; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - He has been in bed with inflammation of the chest and has been bled twice, 1831, December 31; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lafayette to "Justin", 1831; ADS (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lafayette to M. Charles Comte about a new scheme of election laws, 1831; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lafayette to Cassin - Bad news from Poland, 1832, January 26; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette - On the stirring adventure of his aide-de-camp Col. Pogue, when sent to watch the movements of the Royal Troops and to take possession of the diamonds of the Crown, 1832, January 26; ADS (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Claude Joseph Rouget de Lisle to Mr. Duponchel, 1832, January 26; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - ? to John B. Parker, 1832, January 30; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette's Power of Attorney to Nicholas Biddle, 1832, March 15; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Biddle - Text of letter on exhibition in the Lafayette Room of Henry Ford's Wayside Inn at Sudbury, MA, 1832, March 18; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Deputy Coulmann - Calling a meeting to consider a monument to Benjamin Constant, 1832, April 4; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - "An Alien Bill against refugees has been adopted a deplorable Session", 1832, April 10; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau - THe French Political Situation, 1832, April 19; Photostat 3 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Biddle - News of the cholera epidemic, 1832, April 30; Photostat 4 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bureaux de Pusy to ?, 1832, May 4; ADS (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette about Nicolas Le Fevre (?) - Calls attention to the neglect of a Presentation Medal to one of his old proteges, 1832, May 22; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes bookseller's description and typed translation into English
    - Lafayette to his brother-in-law de Grammont - "We are under martial law", 1832, June 9; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Comte de Montlosier - Discussing the French Revolution and particularly Lafayette and Bailly, 1832, June 11; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes bookseller's description and handwritten translation into English
    - A five page letter on important questions of the day. Lafayette to Sparks, 1832, June 17; Photostat 4 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Jared Sparks - "The British Parliamentary Reform did a great step in the cause of Liberty", 1832, June 28; Photostat 3 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Duponceau introducing an old Colonel Boudet of Artillery who wishes to become a farmer in the United States, 1832, June 29; ADS (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Mrs. George Washington Parke Custis - 4th of July Dinner...cholera is abroad in the land, 1832, June; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lafayette to Madame Malibran, 1832, August 2; Photostat 3 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Malibran, 1832, August 13; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Charles Coquerel - Comments on Gouverneur Morris and his conduct in Paris during the French Revolution - "His aristocratic opinion and his relations with the Court and the old Nobility have done much harm in indicating that my democracy goes far beyond that of the United States", 1832, August 27; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Includes summary of contents and typed translation into English
    - Lafayette to Smith, 1832, September 2; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Official "Certificat National" - signed by Lafayette, 1832, September 12; Printed document with autograph fill-ins, signed (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Samuel F.B. Morse - On the Polish Relief matter, 1832, September 11; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Malibran, 1832, September 13; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to de Neuville - The military situation in Portugal, 1832, September 18; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Madame d'Arusmont (Fanny Wright), 1832, September 27; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Monsieur Lairis Decombe, 1832, September 27; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Samuel F.B. Morse, 1832, September 27; Photostat 3 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Biddle, 1832, October 8; Photostat (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cadwaller David Colden to Governor Vroom, 1832, October 10; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      "Cadwallader David Colden, 1769-1834, grandson of Cadwallader Colden. This interesting letter dated Jersey City 1832 and written in the office of the Morris Canal and Banking Company on Grand Street, and which building is still standing, is addressed to Governor Vroom of New Jersey. It tells of the Canal being just opened and of the trip that an official party had just made from Newark, N.J. to Easton, PA in twenty-nine working hours."
    - Lafayette to James Paul Cobbett - On Portugal Affairs, 1832, October 14; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette - In the interest of the son of the late Berthier de Bernay, 1832, October 15; ADS 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette to Madame Malibran - On her great success in Naples, 1832, October 25; Photostat 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)